Sachin Sasi

sachnsas@gmail.com & Portfolio & +91 8140811899 & Bengaluru, India

As a video creator with 4 years of professional experience and 3 years of freelance work, I bring expertise in screenwriting, cinematography, video editing and sound design. My passion for storytelling drives me to constantly find new and creative ways to bring a story to life on screen. Currently, I oversee the entire video project process, including pre-visualization, indoor/outdoor and VFX shoots, working with animators and directing to ensure maximum output. I am confident in my ability to bring your vision to life.

WORK EXPERIENCE

BYJU'S Think & Learn Pvt Ltd

Sep. 2018 - Mar. 2023

Sr. Creative Specialist, Brand Creative Strategy & Design

Bengaluru

- Overseeing project management and creative direction for all video formats
- Taking client brief and utilising a metric-based approach for ideation and content delivery
- Achieved exceptional lead generation and click-through rates, resulting in conversions
- Experience in creating narrative videos, explainers, and testimonial interviews
- Expertise in film direction, cinematography, editing, and digital intermediate

National Institute Of Design

May. 2018 - Jun. 2018

Design Associate Ahmedabad

- Developed a comprehensive story for sustainable textiles in the form of a short documentary
- Conducted interviews with artisans and weavers in remote locations of Ahmedabad and Kutch
- Gathered information to comprehend the collaboration between students and artisans
- Arranged and managed equipment, crew and shoot plan from pre-production to delivery

Somfy India Pvt. Ltd Mar. 2018 – Apr. 2018

Video Creator

Ahmedabad

Developed concept and screenplay for a promotional video

ZR Productions May. 2016 – Jul. 2016

Associate Cinematographer

Ahmedahad

Created a hyperlapse music video for a Gujrati feature film.

EDUCATION

National Institute Of Design

Jan. 2018

Bachelor of Design (B.Des), Film/Video Production and Communication

Ahmedabad

- Completed 2 short films, 2 documentaries, and 2 advertisements from script to screen
- Acquired hands-on experience and improved technical proficiency in film-making and production processes

AWARDS, SKILLS & INTERESTS

• Excellerators Award - BYJU'S Achievers' Club, for consistent high quality across work products

Mar. 2022

Cinema Experimenta - Signs Film Festival, Federation of Film Societies of India-Keralam

Oct. 2015

- o 'Magic Print' (Design film) won John Abraham National Awards for cinema experimenta
- Professional Skills: Creative direction; strategy; film direction; casting; recruiting; photography; cinematography; screenplay; storyboard; research; content development; art direction; lighting; project management; sound design; video editing; colour correction; colour grading; director of photography
- Software Skills: Adobe Premiere Pro; Da Vinci Resolve; Adobe Audition; Adobe After Effects;
- Interests: Motorcycling; travelling; coffee; clubbing; exercise; film buff